A good goodbye... It's all that matters.
Goodbye June is a drama film directed by Kate Winslet.
Four siblings' lives change drastically when their ailing mother
takes a turn for the worse over the holiday season.
June, played by Helen Mirren.
Helen, played by Toni Collette.
Connor, played by Johnny Flynn.
Molly, played by Andrea Riseborough.
Bernie, played by Timothy Spall.
Julia, played by Kate Winslet.
Goodbye June is a 2025 Christmas family drama film directed by Kate Winslet in her
directorial debut, from a screenplay written by her son Joe Anders.
It stars an ensemble cast that includes Toni Collette, Johnny Flynn, Andrea
Riseborough, Timothy Spall, Helen Mirren, and Winslet herself.
The film is set during Christmas, in which the characters gather around their
dying mother, and confront themes of grief, reconciliation, and love.
Winslet explained that she had not initially intended to direct, but after reading Anders'
script she decided to take on the role of director as well as actor and producer.
She emphasised the therapeutic nature of the story, describing it as "about family, not just about death." Winslet selected several department heads who were newcomers,
including composer Ben Harlan, production designer Alison Harvey, and costume designer Grace Clark, reflecting her desire to give opportunities to emerging talent.
Winslet also adopted unconventional filming methods, such as using small microphones on actors
instead of traditional boom equipment, to create a more intimate atmosphere on set.
Goodbye June was released in select cinemas in the United Kingdom and United States on
12 December 2025, and had its streaming on Netflix from 24 December.
The film explores themes of dreary, compassionate, sympathetic.
The tone is emotional.